[禁商用]
听译: @小小耳朵的梦想 @熊熊小馒头 @TodayMao @万能青年杨奇
时间轴: @_牧悠 @熊熊小馒头
@TodayMao @万能青年杨奇
审核: @_牧悠 @头晕头
特效, 压制: @头晕头
TranSkate联系方式
新浪微博: @特兰斯科传媒
TranSkateStudio@gmail.com
TranSkate自2011年10月成立以来, 专注于滑板滑雪
冲浪等极限运动的视频翻译和宣传推广, 隶属于特兰斯科传媒
动力
世界上最顶尖的滑手每年都会
来到纽约为了荣誉而战-
"街头联赛"决赛
但只有8人能进入最后的决赛
2011年 "街头联赛"决赛
男解说员: 这个赛季一开始我们总共有24位滑手参加
Male Narrator: Man, we started off with 24 skaters in the beginning of the season
现在只有8位滑手进入了决赛来争夺最后的冠军
eight now have the opportunity to call themselves the champion
我知道这激动人心的一刻就是你开创这个比赛的原因
Rob Dyrdek, I know this is what you bulid Street League
Rob Dyrdek你现在是怎么想的
for these monments your thoughts
Rob Dyrdek: 是的 赢下这场比赛你就能得到20万美元的奖金
Rob Dyrdek: This is truly what its about $200,000 in the title of Street League champion
Street League(以下简称SL)是职业滑板界中水准最高的赛事
Street League is the highest level of professional competitive skateboarding
Steve Berra: 直到SL比赛的出现 滑板的竞技性才被人们重视起来
Steve Berra: The competition aspect of skateboarding that up really until Street League
不过滑板的竞技性就那么重要吗?
was it really all that important?
在此之前 滑板的赛制很不完善
Pri to this it was really antiquated system
男解说员: 我们来看他要做什么
Male Narrator: Let's see what he's got
噢!
Oh!
Colin Kennedy: 甚至连桌球比赛的奖金都比滑板多...
Colin Kennedy: Even a billiards champion upon until...
职业滑手在SL中获得的奖金是其他滑板比赛的2倍或3倍
Street League basicly were getting paid double and triple what a professional skateboarder would make in a competition
男解说员: Bastien Salabanzi他成功了!
Male Narrator: Yeah! That is Bastien Salabanzi!
Rob Dyrdek说过至少他会给那些滑手一个机会
Colin Kennedy: Rob Dyrdek said at least let me give these guys an opportunity to make a living
来改变自己的命运
like to change their life
他们赢得了SL的比赛
you could win a Street League contest to
就不用为买房子发愁了
and there's your house down payment
男解说员: 天哪
Male Narrator: Oh man
Chaz Ortiz: 当然想赢下这场比赛
Chaz Ortiz: Of course it will be doubt to win
20万美金
200 grand
这可不是一笔小数目
it's a lot money
Rob Dyrdek: SL决赛是全滑板界里
Rob Dyrdek: You come to Street League champion the most prestigious thing
最负有威望的滑板比赛
that can happen in all of competitive skateboarder
Paul Rodriguez: 每个参赛选手
Paul Rodriguez: Every guy is there at Street League
都是这个星球上最有实力的
is as good as who gets on this planet on earth
男解说员: 这是Sean Mlato, Nyjah Houston
和Chris Cole三个人最后的对决
Male Narrator: It's a three man race between Sean Mlato, Nyjah Houston and Chris Cole
Rob Dyrdek: 我想让8个人参加最后决赛
Rob Dyrdek: I wanna to make where 8 guys make it to the championship
最终的冠军赢得所有的奖金
and the winner to take all
正因如此
This way
每年的 Street League都是滑板史上最重量级的赛事
each year the biggest contest in the history of skateboarding
不管你这一年中表现的有多好
It doesn't matter how good you've done all year
都要看比赛那天的表现是否出众
can you be the best on this day
如果你做到了
If you are
那你就是永远的冠军
you are the champion forever
男解说员: 冠军就要产生了
Male Narrator: Championship moment is right here
让我们看看他能不能顶住压力
stay for high let's see if he can hold on
天哪!
Oh! Oh my God!
Sean Malto是我们的新冠军
Sean Malto is our new champion
兄弟们为他欢呼吧
you guys homies got give him laugh
他获得了冠军
He is the champion
女士们先生们 为他喝彩吧
Give it up, ladies and gentlemen
2011年 "街头联赛"冠军
一年后
密苏里州 堪萨斯城
我第一次参加比赛时12 13岁的样子
This was just the first contest that I was like 12 or 13
这张照片很有意思 我和父母在一起野餐
this is funny 'cause my parents just rolled up like had food, like picnic
还带了遮阳伞 躺椅 冰镇饮料
umbrella, longchairs, cooler
我的父母都很享受SL
and like my mom and dad are
so good all the Street Leagues
他们每场比赛都会去看
they are at every contest they don't leave
凡是我参加的比赛他们几乎每场都会在现场
they've been to almost every contest I've ever been in
所以他们对我滑板的支持从未间断
so there's always been supportive
they are always done for skating
"卫冕冠军"
距离决赛还有3周
在他赢下比赛后的一年中很多东西都改变了
A lot has changed in the year since he won
对他个人来说就是赞助商
for him personally in terms of sponsors and
以及别人对他的期望
probably what's expected of him
他刚得到Nike的赞助
He just got on Nike
而Nike就是致力于把选手送上领奖台
and Nike is about putting people on the podium
我觉得
I would say
在场的每个人都有可能赢得最终的比赛
every single one of these guys are in there can win
这个比赛的可怕之处在于一切都在比赛的那天尘埃落定
that's what scary about this contest all comes down in the day
在于那天你的状态怎么样
how you feel that day
在于那天你的脚感有没有来
how the board falls in your feet that day
那天的压力会非常大
You see people under pressure
是那种平时你真的很难感受到的压力
that you don't really get to see under pressure that often,
而这对世界上最棒的滑手而言 或多或少是件好事
it's more or less free for all of the best skaters in the world
真疼啊
That hurt
街头滑板就是在各种地方找好玩的地形去滑
Street skating is just all about finding cool spots all around the world
这才是滑板真正的意义
just that are really meant for skating
警察总局
Rob Dyrdek: Sean Malto的能力非常全面
Rob Dyrdek: Sean Malto is all style in class
他曾经赢过很多比赛 但他从不对外提起这些
he is the guy that onced win really bad and never shows on the outside
他实力相当强
He is just incredibly competitive
"街头联赛"创始人
这就是他之前战胜往届冠军夺得第一的原因
and that's why he has been the champion before one of the guy who has won before
Colin Kennedy: 很明显这就是他去年为什么赢得比赛
Colin Kennedy: It's obvious why he won last year
成功率很高 整场比赛都没有失误
Sean was consistent,
he didn't fall for the whole contest
摄影师
他是唯一没有失误的
I mean he is the only guy to not bail
他也许不会去做那些技巧性很强 或很疯狂的招
He might not done the most technical trick the craziest trick
但是他会一直不停的尝试
but that means Sean could do it again
放松 放松
So you need relax
棒极了
That's great
加州 拉古那海滩
[注意车牌"DMND63"]
我的小兔子
"神童"
男音: 你拿的是什么
Male voice: Wow, what do we got here
Nyjah母亲: 很意思他要照顾(一只兔子)
Nyjah's mom: This is funny he has custody of...
Nyjah母亲的家
男音: 谁的兔子
Male voice: Whose bunny?
男音: 真可爱啊
Male voice: That's sweet
Nyjah Huston: 看看
Nyjah Huston: Right there
-是谁养的   -Whose is it?
-我的   -It's mine
Nyjah母亲: 不对
Nyjah's mom: No
有个妹子送给他一只兔子
但后来他们不再联系 现在我们来养它了
男音: 它长得真大
Male voice: She's got big
Nyjah母亲: 它叫Ripta
Nyjah's mom: Her name's Ripta
Nyjah Huston: 这是他们给第一名的巨额支票
Nyjah Huston: The big check that they give you for first place
有趣的一点在于 SL一般情况下
It's crazy 'cause in Street League like normally in contest
第一名 第二 三名都会有奖杯
you'll get like first place or second or third place trophy went on
但如果你没得第一的话会很沮丧
but like it feels you're so bumped when you don't win Street League
因为除了跟第一名都拿奖杯之外 你什么也没有
'cause you only get like a trophy that kinda stuff for first place you know
这就是那个奖杯了
That's the big guy right there
希望今年还能再拿一个回来
Hopefully it will get another one this year
去年没能赢下冠军
missed that one last year
这东西特别重 几乎搬不动 太疯狂了
The thing's so heavy like can't be carried, it's insane
这是2010年的奖杯
Yeah, that's 2010 one
我当然特别想赢得这个比赛
I definitely wanna win it really bad
因为去年我赢得了前三站的冠军
because what happened last year I won the first three
但很不走运 最后一站却没拿下
and unfortunately wasn't able to win the last one
所以没能成为总冠军
so I wasn't the overall champion
Nyjah母亲: 这是在Davis那里拍的
Nyjah's mom: This image you see Davis doing
嗯... 该怎么说  Davis拍的下六阶
uhh what is that, the Davis six
这个扶手很出名 很多人去那玩
It's there famous rail, guys still getting to that
我都不知道这是什么时候拍的了
I don't have a date on this one
Nyjah Huston: 当时我7岁
Nyjah Huston: Yeah, I was seven
Nyjah母亲: 是吗
Nyjah's mom: Seven?
Nyjah Huston: 没错
Nyjah Huston: Yeah
那时候你正在拍第一部"赞助我"的视频吧
This's like when you film your first "Sponsor-Me" tape, right?
是啊
Yeah
Nyjah的"赞助我"视频
以前那儿有个滑板场
There was an old skatepark
离我们家大概15分钟路程
that was about 15 minutes from our house
我们常常带着孩子去那练习
and we were take our kids there to practice
Nyjah的母亲
是个室内滑板场
It was an indoor park
很破旧
it was pretty run down
到后来板场的所有者不想再经营了
but we ended up getting another owner they wanna out
我们便从他们手里买下了这个板场
so we bought the skatepark from them
我们全家每星期有6天都在那度过
So we were there six days a week as a family
当然当时他才7岁的样子
and of course he was like a 7-year-old kid
太小什么都做不了 所以就整天都在滑板
what's he gonna do? Since he skated all day
这是我的4个孩子和他们的父亲 全副武装
Those are the 4 boys, their dad, all geared up
毫无疑问 滑板是整个家庭的活动
so it's definitely a family affair
Colin Kennedy: Nyjah的父亲从他4岁时就
Colin Kennedy: Nyjah's dad pretty much shape Nyjah into this
就开始培养他成为一个滑板机器
kind of nonestop skateboarding machine from the age of 4
[小Nyjah的笑声]
[Little Nyjah's laugh]
小孩音: 耶!
Kid voice: Yeah!
Rob Dyrdek太了不起了...
Rob Dyrdek is awesome...
是的 你给了我很大的激励
Yeah, you inspired me very much
"街头联赛"创始人
我能拍几张照片吗
Can I get a couple of photos?
这个图案是我去年见到你之后纹的
This one is kind of worn off already
现在看起来已经有点不清楚了
because it was right after I met you last year
你有没有一直做好事呢
and then did you really do everything kind?
我可是记得要去做个好人
So I remember to be kind
还有这个
and then you'r C-List
Rob Dyrdek: 哇哦
Rob Dyrdek: Wow
太不可思议了
Unbelievable, man
女音: 我还想把这个纹在身上
Female voice: and I want to have this tatoo on me
还没机会去弄
I didn't have the chance
Rob Dyrdek: 天呐
Rob Dyrdek: Oh man
这是我去年和她说的话
This's what I said last year
去年他叫我别纹身
Last year he told me no tatoo
你没听进去啊
You just treat defying
女音: 就是这样的 必须的 哈哈
Female voice: Defying, that's right, damn it
Rob Dyrdek: 估计接下来就会把我的名字和脸纹在一起了 天啊
Rob Dyrdek: All next level will get my name and my face on it God
Eric Koston: Rob Dyrdek总是会花费心思来搞些新东西出来
Eric Koston: Rob Dyrdek he's always got his hands in some sort of pot trying to create something
特别是在我们不能提供给滑手们丰厚物质回报的时候
that really comes when we weren't making a lot of money for skateboarders you know
我十分尊重Rob
I have much respect for Rob putting a...
他开创SL 把竞技滑板提升到了一个更高的水平
just starting Street League and really taking contest skating for the next level
创造了一些全所未有的东西
creating something that completely new
他很早就一直在想怎么来做好SL
He's been talking about doing Street League
早到他还没有被大众以现在的身份所熟知之前
since before he was ever the guy that people in pop culture know him as now
女音: 我的天啊
Famale voice: Oh my god
不好意思 我能抱一下你吗
I'm sorry, can I have a hug?
Rob Dyrdek: 没问题 来吧
Rob Dyrdek: Hug it out, it's hugging
女音: 我妈妈很喜欢你...
Female voice: Oh my God, my mom loves you...
刚开始我接触到滑板场工程
Initially I first took on sort of skatepark industry right
就建了世界上第一个滑板广场
I build the world first skate plaza
它坐落于我的家乡俄亥俄州
and built in my hometown in Ohio
当时世界上最厉害的职业滑手都来了
All the world's best pros came out
是在2005年
this was in 2005
Chirs Cole赢得了第一 奖金是$15,000
and it was $15,000 first prize that Chris Cole won,
这些都为之后建立的SL奠定了基础
that was sort of the pilot what Street League would eventually become
小孩音: 谢谢你举办了这么好的比赛
也谢谢你 希望你玩得开心
Thank you, hope you enjoy yourself
我会的
I will
Colin Kennedy: 他基本上做的都是那些小众化的东西
Colin Kennedy: He's basicly taking something that's always been on the fringes
像滑板一样
you know skateboarding
而他一直在努力把它打造成为主流
and he is thursting it to the main stream
Rob Dyrdek: 这可不是场普通的滑板比赛
Rob Dyrdek: This is not just a skateboarding contest
这里是滑板的"街头联赛"
this is Street League skateboarding
Colin Kennedy: 这不是一个简单的小比赛
Colin Kennedy: This isn't a small production
8位精英职业滑手
冠军将赢得20万美金
他每年都会在比赛中投入巨额资金
So he is like putting ton of money into each of these
1个冠军
但没人敢保证这个比赛会被人们接受
and there's no guarantee that it's gonna catch on
Steve Berra: 他在上面投入了大量的精力
Steve Berra: He's got some much riding on it
他在里面投入的钱
he's giving away more money than probably,
比八九十年代所有比赛加起来还要多
all the contest in the entire 80's and 90's together
这就是一场赌博
This is a gamble
没人愿意看到自己的梦想破灭
You know the last thing you wannna do is fail your dream
加州 圣克莱门特
Ryan Sheckler: 嘿...
Ryan Sheckler: Hey...
嘿 Dean
hey Dean
[之前Redbull为Sheckler拍摄的"Sheckler Sessions"中就是这只狗狗被绑在一堆气球上带上了天 当然飞离地面的高度在可控的范围之内]
这就是那只飞上天的狗
This is the flying dog
真乖 真乖
Yes yes
来 打个哈欠
Give us another yawn
还突然亲我呢
Random mouth, Random mouth
"明星"
男音: 他拍了绝对不止6张照片才得到这些
Male voice: He shoot a lot more than 6 photos to get this
这就是最好的奖杯的聚集处
the best athlets knocked over together
我觉得给你设计这款手表嘛
So you know for you I think
我们将很多东西放在一起做成了这块情绪板
with this watch like we put these together like a mood board
将一些配色 照片 还有你的肖像印在纸上
some of the color treatment we put on the photos
用黄色会让人感觉更显眼
and portraits can have like this kind of yellow illuminate and feel
Ryan Sheckler: 对
Ryan Sheckler: Right
男音: 用黄色会让人感觉更显眼
Male voice: and portraits can have like this kind of yellow illuminate and feel
或者放一些硬件图案
maybe like some hardware
比如Plan B的工具啊 汽车 头带之类的
Plan B skate tool, cars and like you know from your bands or...
你还留着那个吗
Do you still have before it?
我借给 Steve 的一个朋友了
Yeah I do, Steve has a dawg and I let him borrowed it
没关系
OK
他给了我一对桥
he treated me his truck
首先得是那些你觉得有意义的东西
First like any objects that means things to you
很多东西都会有这种私人情节
you know lot stuff shows that personal touch
Ryan Sheckler: 确实
所以我把这个放在房间里 看起来特别柔和
Ryan Sheckler: Right, so I thought this puts in this room, it's pretty mellow
这是我祖母给我做的
My grandma makes this for me
她做了很多 我都把它们挂在我房间的墙上
so many of them they all hug up in my room
嘿 看呐
Oh, look at that
我祖母居然在那放了一张星巴克的百元券
grandma just hooked me up that with a hundred dollar gift to certificate to Starbucks
我都不知道放了有多久
how long that's been there?
男音: 拍这张照片时你多大
Male Voice: How old are you in that photo?
8岁
Eight
Ryan在很小的时候就成了一个商人
Colin Kennedy: Ryan at a super early age became basicly a businessman
Ryan Sheckler: 上一集Ryan的生活
Ryan Sheckler: Last season life of Ryan
男主持: 你们准备好迎接Ryan Sheckler了吗
Host: Are you ready to meet Ryan Sheckler?
Colin Kennedy: 他经常上些电视节目
Colin Kennedy: It only had TV shows like
而这些和滑板一点关系都没有
all these things that kind of have nothing to do with him on skateboard
Ryan Sheckler: 我的滑板事业带我走遍了世界各地
Ryan Sheckler: My career took me all over the world
我也从中学到了不少东西
and I learned a lot
我明白了我越成功...
I learned the more successful I became...
男主持: 欢迎来自圣克利门蒂的Ryan Sheckler参加我们的节目
Host: Ryan Sheckler from San Clemente joins us
...我的生活会变得越疯狂
...the more crazier my life got
Rob Dyrdek: 这让他迅速成为了一个巨星
Rob Dyrdek: It catapulted him into superstar
Ryan的生活
他是一个非常活跃的职业滑手
He's dynamic the professional skateboarder
和圈里之前情况的完全不同
is unlike anything in history
男摄影师: 你把它撕下来时再看看它有没有贴好
Male filmer: Before you peel that off just like been done kind of inspect it again if you just doing
Steve Berra: 因为他能吸引很多女生
Steve Berra: Because he has such female teenage can glamour that loves him
而且作为一个名人 他承担很多责任
and all these obligations that he has as like a celebrity
他不能像别人那样花那么多时间滑板
it does take away from his ability to skate as much as some other guys
Ryan Sheckler: 这太闷了  我们快点拍完
Ryan Sheckler: Oh I can't even breath, let's do this quick
男摄影师: 好的
Male filmer: OK
这些的确对他比赛的输赢有所影响
And it affects his ability to win this contest
男摄影师: 再拍一张
Male filmer: One more
搞定 很好
Alright, cool
Ryan Sheckler: SL的冠军纯粹就是自我激励
Ryan Sheckler: The victory of Street League is purely self motivated feeling
你就是想赢 就是获得那座奖杯
you just wanna do it, just to have that trophy
我不知道那种感觉会是怎么样 因为我还没有得到过
I don't know what it feels like 'cause I haven't
所以我还不能体会到那种
So I can't imagine that it would be one of
比赛以后如释重负的感觉
those weigh off your chest finally happen, it's done
加州 伍德兰希尔斯
Paul Rodriguez: 不管有没有比赛
Paul Rodriguez: With or without competition
我每天都会去滑板 这就是我的生活
I skateboard everyday, that's just my life
"职业滑手"
我-我从不会为比赛去准备
I-I'm never preparing for a contest
我只是为了滑板而滑板
I'm always trying prepare for skateboarding
我就是为了让我的技术变得更好
My goal is perfecting skateboarding which is not possible
你不可能做出所有的招
you can never do everything there is to do
但是我会努力去做 更加刻苦的练习
but I approch like maybe one if I practice harder
花更多的时间 也许有一天我能做出能难的招
ever try long enough maybe one day I will
这就是让我充满动力的原因
you know that's what keeps me hungry
我只是希望自己能做个更棒的滑手
I just try prepare be a better skateboarder
如果我一直这么做 理论上说来
and in theory if I'm doing that
所有的这些比赛 不论最后我是否获胜
everything else all this goals,
potential competition wins were or not
都已不再那么重要
should falling place on their own
你能持续提高自身滑板的唯一途径就是
Steve Berra: The only way that you can continue to progress skateboarding is
自己给自己施加压力
if you have internal self-imposed pressure
因为不会有人强迫你去练习
'cause there's no one else telling you to do it
也不会有人强迫你去下台阶或是呲杆子
there's no one else to tell you to jump down this stairs or get on this handrail
强迫你花上3个小时去练好Manual或者台子的动作
spend 3 hours on this manual or ledge trick
给自己压力的唯一的人就是你自己
The only person is putting pressure on you is you
我要确保以最好的状态去参加SL
Paul Rodriguez: Try make sure and go in Street League feeling are 100% physically
全神贯注
just give my mind focus on it
相比其他赛事 我会更加虔诚地祈祷
I just give a real strong prayer more than any competition
我十分虔诚地相信耶稣所说的一切
I really admire and really believe
things that Jesus spoke about
耶稣是我现实生活的精神支柱
and Jesus was my entry-level inter spiritual reality
我看着耶稣
So I look at Jesus
他让我看到了希望
you know he is the dawn
加州 埃斯孔迪多
高了
Damn high
这也没射中
That doesn't work either
正中目标
There you go
"宝刀不老"
你看过这个吗
Have you seen this?
Chris的妻子: 就一直做这个动作吗
Chris' wife: This? Just all of them?
Chris Cole: 是啊
Chris Cole: Yeah
Chris的妻子
我记得是
I think so
应该都是这个动作吧
Just the all of them
我觉得这可以代表我的风格吧
I guess that's like that's always
kind of like being my role
怎么说呢
like I don't know
现在很多人能做这招
There's always somebody that can do tricks
不过我想我的风格就是这样不放弃
you know I guess my kind of role ways been
我非常喜欢滑板
I absolutely love skating
我会继续滑下去 不需要理由
and then I'll continue until far beyond reason
就是这样
you know
我不会放弃
it could like never give up thing
现在的话
and like nowadays
我会更理性地去选择挑战的动作
I'll pick and choose my battles a little bit wiser
我花了3个多小时不断尝试这个动作
it was like I was gonna try it until I made it
最后终于成功了
so it was like 3 hours
就这个动作
I've trying the thing
有趣的是
It was funny too
我不记得我是怎么做成那个动作的了
the one that I made I don't remember making
我只记得我一直在尝试
I remember trying it the time and the one I made
当我站上滑走之后 我几乎要昏过去了
like I was almost blackout and I was riding away
其实可以更谨慎点的
You kinda have to have smarts about it
你完全没必要摔这么多次
that was- that was unnecessary
不过你可不能在同一个地方犯错
but it was unnecessary like slaming the same way
那可痛了
So it's a lot pain
但那些都过去了
but it's over
我告诉自己以后不能再这样了
I told myself that I would
never do anything like it again
Colin Kennedy: 有趣的是其实Chris一点都没变老
Colin Kennedy: It's funny cause Chris is not old by any means
不论在SL还是其他的比赛
but in the contest of Street
League and in the contest
他都是强有力的冠军争夺者
who he is obvious against
for the championship
他是个老兵
He's the older guy
Chris Cole: 我的身体已大不如前
Chris Cole: It's funny 'cause my body's changed
现在我总会感到酸痛
and it's get sore now
我年轻时不会有这种感觉
like it didn't get sore when I was a kid
不过现在我已经习惯了
now I'm used to it
习惯了酸痛 身体始终都是酸痛的
being sore, all the time sore
我曾经把Chris Cole形容成森林里横冲直撞的大熊
Rob Dyrdek: I once describe Chris Cole as a bear running to the forest tearing down trees
他就像是一个巨人
he's just like a giant man
他在现实中非常厉害
and you know in the reality he's so good
按理说他是整个联赛中最强的人
arguably the best guy in the entire league
面对几乎赢掉所有滑板赛事的众多对手
again another massive competiter who's won everything in all of skateboarding
他曾经有机会赢得SL
and has the chance to win
the Street League contest
很可惜的是他在最后一个动作上失误了
on different occasions he's on his fianl trick and did not land that trick
男解说员: Chris失误了
Male Narrator: Oh It gets away the Cobra
他没能迎来他的第一个冠军
So he will not get his first win
宾夕法尼亚州 Woodward营地
这个板场与世隔绝 非常不错
It's so nice here, 'cause it's in the middle of nowhere
你环顾四周后 一定会说 这太棒了
You just looked around and it was just like...so sick!
这就可以说是滑手的天堂
Pretty much it's just like a dreamland for skaters
什么样的地形都有
just everything you want
我在这里参加过一次夏令营 并参加了比赛
I came here as a camper once and skated a contest
那时我大约8岁
I was probaly like a 8 dude
比赛得了第二名
and end up like taken 2nd place
那是我第一次参加woodward夏令营
and that was the first time I came as a camper
我记得我当时特别想家
I remember I got so homesick
我让父母开了14小时的车来接我
I had my parents come to pick me up
it was like a 14 hours drive
我也不知道
I don't know
跟着那几个跑着的小朋友
他们应该知道地方
Go with these kids are running
I think they are going somewhere
他们去寻宝了 所以跟着他们
They go on the hunt ,so...
小孩音: 我找到一件T恤
Kid voice: I found a T-shirt
你找到的吗
You found one?
是的
Yeah!
在哪找到的
Where?
在一棵树下面
Under a tree
哈哈 不错
haha, sick!
小孩音: 我也真想找一件
Kid voice: I really want to find one
他们正在去找呢
They are going right now
我也不知道 跟着他们去找吧
I don't know, go follow them
我有一段时间没赢过比赛了
I haven't won a contest in a while
我想那就是我真心追求的东西
I think that's what I really work for
只是...
It's just like...
失败的感觉真不好
you just have that feeling bad
"新生力量"
那次比赛本应志在必得了
It's out for the taking you know
但倒霉的是我犯了个小错误 就是这样...
but what's bad is one little mistake and it's...that's it..
男解说员: Chaz Ortiz现在位于第二名
Male Narrator: Chaz Ortiz in second place
如果这招没成 那么Nyjah Huston会再次夺冠
If he does not land the trick, Nyjah Huston wins again
未来15年 Chaz Ortiz将成为SL的领军人物
He will be a top level professional street skater in Street League for the next 15 years
最起码15年
at least
直到他30多岁 体能下滑的时候
Till his 30's, till his body starts breaking down
Chaz Ortiz: 滑板最酷的就是一切都得靠自己
Chaz Ortiz: What's cool about skating is no one can skate for you
你就是你的整个团队
You are your own team
Chaz Ortiz出招的成功率真是太高了
Chaz Ortiz he is just, man he is so damn consistent
Rob Dyrdek: 他是如此的优秀
Rob Dyrdek: As good he is
却不像其他滑手那么出名
he doesn't have that upper rush long respect that all the other guys have
他一直在百折不挠地证明
And he is relentlessly finding the prove
自己是一个顶尖滑手
that he is one of these lead
而赢得SL则能证明这一点
And winning the contest will do that for him
法国 波尔多
Bastien Salabanzi: 噢 天啊
Bastien Salabanzi: Oh man
对于Bastien
For Bastien
和联盟其他选手相比 他要承受太多太多的坚持了
the sticks so much higher than anyone else in the league
他们中一些人收入都过百万
Some of these guys made millions of dollars
而他只是能维持生计而已
And he is the guy just still...
give him a check just enough to pay rent
他得去板场拍视频
He had to go on film in a skatepark
赢得观众投票后 才能来到美国
get voted in Europe to even get here
"回归的少年"
噢 拉到极限了
It's the limit
我参加了SL欧洲的预选赛
I heard about the EU selection for the Street League
我认识美国那些滑手
我想和过去他们一起比赛
I know those guys, I want to be over
there skating with those guys
这是最高水准的比赛
This is the highest contest
水平高到难以想象
grow up doing...
highest contest you can imagine
然后我得知入选了 所以...
the next thing I know,
they tell me you are on so...
我真的很激动 因为这改变了我的人生
I was really excited about that
for sure 'cause it's life changing
你刚开始推拿的时候
In the middle of foot where you start
我的脚掌心那部分就很酸
you starting pushing, it's kind of soar
对 就是这里
Yeah there
我感觉到里面有点骨裂了
I feel like there's little ruction inside
当你按摩那里的时候
When there is pushing
就会发出"咳啦啦啦"的声音
It was like "kelalala..."
这症状从来就没消失过
and that symptom never goes away
为什么一推拿就这样子呢
Why it happenes when you start pushing?
按摩师: 那是因为你骨头有增生
Massager: Because you have accretions
它会形成各种的形状
that formed a plenty of fashion
这就是你骨裂的原因了
and that's why they break them up
他今年来参赛就是为了赢
He basically came into this league
this year on winning the prayer
还有 你要知道...
and you know really...
我想他甚至为了能够参加比赛
整个过程付出了很多
I think struggles to make him way all the way to even get to the events
另外 比赛的奖金对他来说很重要
and that prize money that
he wins is incredibly important
这钱可以补贴他旅行的开支
you know this pays for his trip
你的腿很灵活嘛
对 我练过几年芭蕾舞
既然参加了SL
Entering Street League for sure
我就要圆满地完成比赛
I mean know I had to pull it off
实际上赢得冠军
Actually winning the championship
对我来说太疯狂了 因为这就像是...
for me it's just insane 'cause it's like...
没错 你复出了
OK you are back
而且复出后还得到了冠军
and now you are back and you are back on the top
Flip滑板影片"Sorry"
Bastien之前是这种风格的
Bastien's kind of like the dude for a while
他拍过一些很棒的视频
He put up amazing parts
我从小看他的视频长大
and I grew and waching him
每次看他滑板 都让我大吃一惊
He blows my mind everytime I watch him skate
他在欧洲是常胜将军
He win contest, always european contest
当他来到美国
come to State side
他就会去街头滑板
He kind of have this like street going
如果Bastien参加了比赛
If Bastien was skating in the contest
他最后一定会站在领奖台上 然后离开
He's definitely walking away, you know on the podium
基本上都是前三名
like top 3 something
之后他就... 消失了
And he kinda just... disappeared
巴西 愉港市
Rob Dyrdek: Luan是滑手中的滑手
Rob Dyrdek: Luan is the skaters' skater
"艺术家"
他做招的方式
the way he does certain tricks
让滑板运动看起来是如此的美
is what made skateboarding so beatiful
他的Hardflip做的非常漂亮
His hardflip is so beautifully done
让观众为之震惊
that stunts the crowd
也震惊了他的对手们
you know it stunts all his peers
这个地形太完美了
可以在上面练习为总决赛做准备 大小很适合
这儿是我的最爱
可以和朋友们一起玩耍 滑板
为比赛热热身
他就像是个会滑板的艺术品
He just like a skating piece of art
这哥们滑的太漂亮了
dude like is, skating is so beautiful
这一定要规定是板尾吗
板头板尾没所谓
那就定做板尾吧
刚做了几个?
4个
7个
第9个没成
Colin Kennedy: 我认为Luan是个非常棒的孩子
Colin Kennedy: I think Luan is a rad kid
我觉得在生活中他已经历了很多的事情
I think he has been through a lot personally in his life
我是被爷爷奶奶抚养长大的 而不是父母
他们给了我很多的帮助 从小就激励着我
他们鼓励我坚持滑板这条路
Rob Dyrdek: 滑板是Luan的救星 也是他真正的前途
Rob Dyrdek: Skateboarding is Luan's savior, man it's really his way
不 伙计 一定要把你拍进来
你就是我生命中的唯一
你要展示下自己啊
我过去住在巴西中部的某个地方 太犀利了
Luan的经理
他从贫民区来!
旁边就是监狱
那儿太有意思了
[Luan在调侃]
so funny there
以前有朋友想去我家看看就问我可不可以
back the days my friend was like ah can I see your house
我说当然可以 在一个叫做阿鲁的贫民窟
Yeah sure, ahlu in a ghetto you know
他就说过去看看
he was like, yeah rad let's go
他到了以后就非常吃惊
when he get there, he was like, damn!
简直是贫民窟中的贫民窟
the ghetto in the ghetto
就是这样的 哈哈
yeah, haha
谢天谢地再也不用住那了
Not anymore, I thank God
我在那见过太多的人死掉
I have seen so manny people dying shit
我从-我从来没想过那个
And I never, never thought that
从没想过像他们那样 不想那样
never thought of one that, no like that
基本就是这样
so you know
之后就是Cesar改变了我的命运
then Cesar changed my life
他帮了我很多
helped my a lot
他每个月都给我食物
He just give me like food every month
就这样坚持了大概3年 我记不太清楚了
for like 3 years like, I'm not sure
每个月啊
Every month you know
还有照顾奶奶那些 太牛逼了
For my, like my grandmother shit, so sick
他帮我太多太多了
helped me a lot, a lot
如果不是滑板
If it wasn't skateboarding
我不知道我现在会在做什么
I don't know what the hell I'm doing right now
可能在贩毒
Probably selling drugs
甚至现在已经死掉了吧
even died probably dead right now
所以我得好好珍惜现在的生活
So I got to think every minute you know
还要珍惜身边的一切 一切
on everything, everything
神奇的是Nyjah从小到大都有这样的习惯
Crazy thing about Nyjah
when he was little and he still likes today
距离决赛还有2周
那就是他的生活数十年如一日
is that he is very routine
所以当我们有了板场之后
so when we have that skatepark
他每天都会来
He would come in everyday
然后按特定顺序练他的那些招
And he would practice his bags
of tricks in a particular order
如果有哪招不成
And he wouldn't let himself move on
他会在做线过程中一直练到成功为止
until he land them all in the middle line
所以他从小就非常的专注
so he was just that focused that young
TranSkate译制
事实上Nyjah他自己在完成这条线之前
And he actually wouldn't allow himself to go have fun and
他是不会去玩耍或者在板场学新动作的
skate learn new stuff in the park till he land this line
我认为Nyjah Huston就像是个沉默的杀手
Nyjah Huston to me is a quiet assassin
他命中注定要成为一名顶尖滑手
And he was born to be a
lead competitive skateboarder
他小时候就不去上学了
he didn't go to school when he was young
在他10岁的时候 他老爸就各种训练他
Just think his dad had trained him on Nollie flips
练那些狠招
Tre flips and kickflip backside tailslide
since he was like ten
这就是为什么他在17岁的时候那么出众
that's why he's so superior at 17
我想老爸对我的训练还是有一些帮助的
I guess it was kind of help down by my dad a little bit
他对我总是很严厉 过分地保护着我
He was always really strict and really protective
他是Nyjah的经理 父亲
He was Nyjah's manager, his father
Nyjah的导师 私人摄影师 也许是摄像师这些
his mentor, you know his peronal filmer,
photographer possibly like
他基本上就是滑板界的全能老兵Earl Woods
He was basically the Earl Woods in skateboard world
我爸几乎每天都去板场
My dad pretty much be at the skatepark everyday
当他没去的时候
but the day he wouldn't be there
我妈妈会说太好了
My mom would say that yes!
你可以出去和朋友滑板玩耍了
you can go out like skating,
have fun with friends
因为那时在板场
'cause when I was there
我爸爸基本上不让我交朋友
my dad pretty much wasn't
allow me to have friends
所以我不得不专心滑板
and that was pretty much
I had to focus on skateboarding
我有时生病了之类的 不想练板了
I would be like sick or something,
I want to choke for the day
他却让我必须去滑板
and he was like
oh you got have to skate
男音: 那你的学业怎么办
Male voice: What about school?
学校?
School?
我爸让我辍学了
My dad kills about school
他要的是让我全身心投入到滑板之中
All he want me is focusing
on skateboarding you know
他甚至不想让我担心学校的事情
He didn't want me even
to worry about going to school
或有备用计划之类的
or having a back up plan
噢 我的腿 啊哦
oh this leg, ouch
男音: 今天做什么治疗呢
Male voice: so what are we working on today?
Nyjah Huston: 是的 就只是膝盖
Nyjah Huston: Oh yeah, just the knee
只有膝盖吗
The knee?
如果必要 治疗下肩膀也会好很多
there's some help with shoulders if it has to
肩膀已经感觉很好了 没问题
It feels good yet, feels good yet
-没任何问题了吗   -No problem at all?
-对   -No
-所以这次就只是膝盖 对吧   -so just the knee?
-没错   -Yeah
你的下次SL比赛是什么时候
这周末
This weekend
总决赛
the final one
总决赛 最重要的一场
最关键的一场
比赛前你基本上已经知道出哪些招了吧
you pretty much know every trick you gonna do for you even started?
基本上都想好了 是的
Basically, basically
应该也会有些备用的招式吧
you would try something will work out as well?
哦 是的 我会有一些其他的选择
Oh yeah, I would have few differnt,
few extra choices
如果一招总是不成 我会换成别的
If one trick doesn't work out, I'll switch it out
是那个部位吗
right there? that knee?
对
Yeah
哦 G 我告诉过你我要搬出去自己住吗
Oh G, did I tell you that I'm gonna live on my own?
你告诉我了Honey Cube什么的
You did, you told me something about Honey Cube?
就是那个
Yeah
这房子有点贵
it's kind of expensive
原因很可能是离沙滩比较近
but probably because this site is close to the beach
离沙滩近吗
Close to the beach?
是的
Yeah
那地方有多大？
How big is that place?
有5个卧室
5 bedroom
哦
Oh!
游泳池也很不错
Pool is goosy
那很多小孩都会想去你那住了
this means all the boys gonna
want to stay in your house
还能玩喝啤酒大赛
play around beer pump
这是个好地方
It's a good place
那样的生活一定很躁
It's like real life ontrash
我觉得你的邻居要遭殃了
I feel certain to ruin your neighbors
感觉怎么样
How's that feel?
很好
good
不错 我准备好去比赛了
Yeah, yeah, they are ready to go
当你有了孩子
When you have a child
一旦孩子出生
as soon as the child was born
当爸爸的马上会有这样的反应
just immediate instinct concern
"你想要什么 你需要什么 我能做什么"
"OK, what do you want, what do you need, what can I do"
"要尿不湿吗 搞定了"
"need a diper? cool done"
"要奶瓶吗 来了"
"need a bottle? done"
当你看到自己的孩子
When you see the child
就会非常非常的爱她
you have it overwhelming, just love
完全是无条件的爱
That's unconditional
你会在乎孩子还需要什么 无论什么都会去做
you just "Yeah whatever you need, yeah what you want?
哦 我明白了
Oh I got you like
就是像这样的 所以...
It's just like that so...
带孩子并不是让你牺牲什么
this thing didn't feel like sacrifice
这肯定是种很特别的感觉
definitly little bit different
尤其是我和她妈妈分居后
especially a little bit different now
since her mother and I seperated
这种变化感觉怪怪的
That adjustment is weird
你们好 哥们
what's up, dudes
嘿
What's up
我找了个新房子 想看看吗
当然想看了
Yeah, alright
我过去七年过的都是以团队为家这种生活
I used to seven years of family home style life you know
所以这种调整就更加棘手
so that's the adjustment that was more tough
因为小女儿不明白我为什么总不在家
Because Heaven didn't understand
why I wasn't at home everyday
为什么我不和她一起住
Why didn't I live there
为什么只是有时才能见到我
Why she would just see me little increments
这一点仍然让我很为难
That is still hard for me
因为她还是会问我
'cause she still always ask me like
你什么时候来陪我
When you come and stay with me Riguez
我要永远和你住在一起
like I want to live with you for ever
我们预约了这一家看房
这个还不错
Yeah, this one I like
楼梯很漂亮 我喜欢那个办公室
nice floor, I like that office
空间还可以
ah, reach my hugeness
他们买了剧院的椅子 但又没弄成剧院的风格
They are the theatre seats, not quite the theatre
我所有的动力都源自买一栋房子
That's my whole motivation is to get a house
我和这些哥们搬到这个地方一起住
'cause you know I moved in
with these guys when we got this place
这只是一个暂时的解决办法
that was just a temporary solution
因为我当时急需要找个住的地方
Because it was a immediate need
I just need somewhere to live
当然我很喜欢和这些朋友一起住
这种感觉也不错
it's been great, obviously
I love my friends and live with them
但是我需要一个家
but I need to get a home
因为我想Heaven和我一直生活在一起
'cause I want Heaven to live with me have the way
这像是霍比特人的门
It looks like a hobbit doors
好的 进来看看
Eh, I see, OK I see
房东说房子不错吗
oh they said termites?
活太糙了
Damn, harsh
我看到有些孩子在奶奶家旁边玩滑板
I saw some kids skate by my grandmother's house
我坐在房子里 心想我就要成为那种人
I was sitting inside and I wanna to be that dude
所以 我就是在那时认识了滑板
so at that moment I was like I knew skateboard
所以我问妈妈要滑板 她是个护士
So I asked my mom, she was a nurse
妈妈很担心 所以不给我买
She was very worried, didn't get me one
而我一再坚持她给我买 我已经对滑板着了魔
And I kept asking, and I was obsessed with skateboarding
就这么等了两年 最终妈妈还是给我买了滑板
For two years, my mother finally get me a skateboard
我可足足等了两年啊
that was a two year event
现在我都无法想象
like right now I can't imagine
我能有那么强的意志力 我妈心想
can't imagine having the will
power that my mom had like
如果我儿子还管我要什么东西
If my son still ask me for something
两年后我必须得给他买
then two years later I got performed
注意屈膝
Bend your knees
到那边去
to that part
滑的真不错
You'r always doing a great job
板碰到脚踝了吧 以后要小心
Yeah hit in your ackle but watch out for that
滑板第一年 我都是自己一个人在家门口玩
For the first year I skated by myself in front of my house
没人和我一起玩
Nobody skated with me
我就在家门口到街道那玩
I skated at street dead in front of my house
从来没去过街区那或者其他地方
Never went around the block or anything
第二年 我开始在街区附近玩
The second year I start to go around the block
就这么绕着街区滑着
like skating around the block
所以有很多活我都以为是我自己发明的
So a lot of tricks I do I thought I made up
但其实早就有人发明出来了
It turned out that some body
have made them up before me
但... 我觉得是我发明的
But... I thought I made them up
因为我是一个人玩
'cause I was all alone
就那么自己琢磨
It's like figuring it out
我把东西拿出来 我不用这个包
OK I'll take my stuff out of it, I don't use it
这包很不错的
It's rad
你就让Dylan多拿两个Sandex手表过来
You just have Dylan ask for couple more Sandex
开会的时候我儿子要用到
So it put up couple more in the
conference for my son you know
最近这四五年
我和父母更加的亲密了
The last four or five years I become
a lot closer with my parents
Ryan的母亲
工作和生活上都有
on both sides
我让妈妈回来 我从未失去过她
I got my mom back, I never really lost her
我就是意识到
Just got the real point
她是我的经纪人 也是我的母亲
She's my manager, and also my mom
你要知道 这一切
And you know the whole thing
还有我的父母以及其他事情
my parents all the stuff was going on
我有些应接不暇了
I just coudn't deal with it
她会给我打电话 比如
You know she call me as
今天有个会要参加
you have this meeting today
然后马上去另一个地方
And then jumping to next cup you know
叭叭叭 说这说那的
bababa saying this and this
有时我想问她 你现在是什么身份
It was like who are you right now
我都不知道该怎么办 像是...
I don't even know like...
我只是觉得她比普通妈妈做的太多了 所以...
So it just got too much business over like actual mother so...
我们一起工作时 一切都很不错
When we handle it, everything was great
我们整个家庭很和睦
we'd great relationship me and my whole family
躁起来
And rock'n roolin'
Ryan的父亲
整理好了吗
Get classified?
好了
Yeah
你去吃饭
You go and eat
然后骑车回来 直接去板场
then come cruise back,
then go straight up to the skatepark
我爸爸是最了不起的家伙
My dad was the most amazing dude out
我和他无话不说
I can talk to him about anything
我比赛的时候他都会到场
He's always be at my contest
我比赛前都会和他聊聊
He's the guy I talk to before I skate
如果我做错了事 我会主动告诉他
If I do wrong I talk to my dad before hand
他能让我冷静下来
He makes me calm,
calms me down
他愿意尽一切力量帮我
He offers me anything
如果他帮不了我
If he can't...
他就会亲吻我 给我个大大的熊抱
He always kiss me and that big bear hug
来表示他对我的支持
means he is always there
我的爸爸总是...
My dad's always been...
当我回首我的人生 他总是给予我激励
Inspiration to me I look up to my whole life
我现在仍然这么觉得
I still do
他给我们建了第一个小坡道
He build up our first ramps
让我第一次踏上滑板
Got me on the first skateboard
如果不是滑板 就没有今天的我
I would be no one without it
Ryan滑的好
Good job Ryan!
要拐弯了
almost got the way to turn
转弯
Turn
很好! 酷!
Good! Cool!
Ryan出生之后 他就一直想要个滑板
When Ryan was born he always want a skateboard
我总想着那玩意太危险了!
I just thought that crap is too dangerous!
但他18个月大的时候
But about 18 months
我就让他趴在滑板上玩了
I took the skateboard off the
hook so put it on the floor
他自己走过去 跪在滑板上面
walked over to it put his knee on it
像滑板车那样玩
start to push like a scooter
到两岁半的时候
And by two and a half
他就能站在滑板上了
He was standing on it
跪在板上滑板 然后站上去
push it like a knee and then get on it
就这么在车库前玩了起来
crawling and bomb the drive way
男音: 嗨 你是谁
Male voice: Hey, who are you?
从此便一发不可收拾
And it never ever ever ended from there
爸爸你拍下来了吗
Dad did you filmed that?
Ryan父亲: 滑的真棒 Ryan
Ryan's dad: That was awesome Ryan!
小时候的Ryan: 我的天哪!
Little Ryan: Holy crap!
他们都不带头盔啊
these guys didn't have that helmets on
Ryan父亲: 我知道 他们太疯狂了
Ryan's dad: I know that wat crazy thing
爸爸 他们像疯子一样 这也是他们的表演吧
Daddy they are psycho dude that's like demo too
Ryan父亲: 成一个 Ryan 哦!
Ryan's dad: Kill it Ryan oh!
我全身心投入
I heard got to into it
来打造一位职业滑手
to create a professional skateboarder
他的妈妈也一样支持他
and neither did his mother
我们会全力支持他滑板
We just got in it and support him
在家里他能下10英尺的U池 但这个...
He got a 10 foot at home he comes off no problem but...
我不知道他敢不敢下来
I don't know he can do it or not
今天别试了 不下这个了
Not today don't do it then
你太紧张了 下来吧 没事的
A lot nerv you get off there,
pal don't worry about it
咱们下次再来玩这个
We will do it next time
看这篇文章
So we got this right here
这实际上是我在滑板杂志上的首个访谈
this is actually my first interview
ever in the skateboard magzine
这个当时也刊登在"Thrasher杂志"上了
It was on Thrasher too
实在是太酷了
It's just actually pretty sick
当时我才9岁 很难想象当时那么小
I was nine years old, it's crazy to think I was that young
那是我第一次尝试好莱坞的16级大杆 做的是feeble grind
first time I skated the Hollywood 16 rail, feeble grind
Nyjah有着和他同龄孩子非常不同的思维
Nyjah has a very different braininess than almost all the kids in his age
我想是从他7 8岁开始
他就一直是大家滑板关注的焦点
Eversince I think he was seven or eight, he was always in the spotlight skating
摄影师
也就是在这整个时期
This whole era right here was kinda
大家开始认识了我
when people first started to
get to know who I was
所以这个确实很重要
Uh, so yeah, definitly very important
我的生活都记录在这上面
Time, my life right there
Nyjah当时作为一个Element旗下的AM滑手 薪水很不错
Nyjah was being paid very well as an amateur skater for Element
或者说相当可观
And it was considerable amount of money
实际上他12岁时作为AM拿的薪水
He was actually getting paid more than
要比他现在拿的薪水还要多
at twelve years old as an amateur than he gets now
他们的父亲Adeyemi决定全家搬往波多黎各
And Adeyemi their father just decided that we were gonna move to Puerto Rico
但是他不想赞助商们知道
but he didn't want any of the sponsors to know
当时Nyjah在Element旗下
Earlier he was great on Element
所有的赞助商都对Nyjah有想法
The whole sponsors coming in
却在他的父亲那出了问题
And then there was a problem with his dad
他的父亲突然向赞助商们索取大笔的钱
His dad suddenly demanded money from his sponsors
我觉得可能一年多于3万美金
like, I think, no more than like 30 grands a year
就像你们要签我儿子
就得每年也付我同样的薪水
Just like if you own my son,
you are gonna pay me 30 grands as well
许多制片人尝试联系Nyjah的父亲 可结果都失败了
我觉得他是真的想把我们兄弟带去波多黎各
I think he really wanted to move me and my brothers there
让我们远离在加州的正常生活
to kinda get us away from being
able to live normal life in Califonia
比如和朋友们一起玩
as like having fun with friends
和女生交往 或是喝酒什么的
getting at the girls, getting to drink like that
过了一段时间 赞助商们问我Nyjah去哪了
After a while, the sponsors were like,
hey, where is Nyjah?
他几乎每个月都会出现在杂志上
You know, like he used to be on
the magazines almost every month
现在我们却从没见过他
And now we've never seen him any more
而我们一直在给他付钱
We are paying him all this money
但是他现在不知去哪了
And he's not around
那是我第一次和他父亲的关系决裂
That was the first time my relationship
with his dad ride us broke up
我感觉Adeyemi在用他的想法来改变Nyjah的未来
And I felt like Adeyemi was putting his opinions in front of what was expected for Nyjah
这就是控制
It's just about control
最终Element的人说他们不能让这种情况持续下去了
Eventually, Element said, we cannot let it go
他们不能继续付钱给Nyjah了
we cannot continue to pay this kid
因为这完全是个无法控制的关系
because it's a completely
unmanageable relationship
赞助商们不想这样
You know, the sponsors
did not want to do that
所以你就会被赞助商们除名
So you got cut from the sopnsors
基本上他就跌出了滑板界
and basically fell of the faith of skating earth
这真的太疯狂了
It's really crazy
因为当时Nyjah那么小 就已经是最好的滑手了
because at a young age he was one of the best already
可是他却突然消失了
And then he just disappeared
当时我并没有和Nyjah一起生活
At that time I wasn't living with Nyjah
孩子们都被送到了波多黎各
They were sent to Puerto Rico
而我在加州 想着我该做些什么
And I was in Califonia,
trying to figure out what I'm gonna do
我儿子的整个职业生涯正在土崩瓦解
My son's whole career was falling apart
他正在失去所有的赞助
He's losing all his sponsors
于是... 所以... 我采用了法律手段
And... so... I took legal action
洛杉矶市中心 梦工厂
[手机来电...]
[Call recieved...]
距离决赛还有1周
说话吧
What's up?
男音: 你好
Male voice: What's going on
进展如何
What do you got for me?
电子版的做好了
Gravures are available,
场地设计师
我们要一起看下这个场馆设计
because we're gonna figure this crap out
发过来看看
Let's see it then
这就是了
There it is
这可能是你最好的作品 伙计
This might be your finest work, man.
这可能是最棒的
This might be the best thing
这可能会是你最棒的作品了!
this might be your finest piece of work!
可以说Rob是第一个人开创了完整室内滑板赛事
He pretty much was the first person to start the whole indoor
有着完美的环境和完美的比赛场地
perfect environment, perfect course hall like contest
这太与众不同了
It makes such a big difference
每次都是新的场地
Each time it's a new course
每次他都会先感受下地形 并做适当调整
And each time he's got himself
have show up and adjust to it
没有人会占优势
Nobody has an advantage
这就是该设计的优点
That's what so good about this design
这和以往所有的滑板比赛都完全不同
It's a complete shift from everything
previous in skateboard contest
这是还未测试的
It's untested
这就像是一个用来尝试的模型
This is like a model that's been kind of try and true
这种东西是无法控制的
This is, you know, unchargable water thing
所以毫无疑问Rob是冒着风险做这件事
So Rob's, he's definitly taking a risk by doing this
这就是"大道具"中预留的滑手摔倒区域
This is what the big section have the bump premiere
这样就可以着地后翻滚缓冲
so now you can roll down
这个"大道具"之所以很棒
The reason this big section is so good is
正是因为征服它的难度很高
it's just a hard big section
男音: 你怎么理解"大道具"
Male voice: What's the big section?
一些大东西 跳下去一点都不好玩
Something big that is not fun to jump down
我在SL中倒在地上时会摔得很惨
When I took a slam in street league,
hit the ground so hard
因为我本来应该是可以滑走的
Because I expected to be rolling away
但突然间 我就屁股着地了
Suddenly, I was like on my ass cheek
简直就是四脚朝天啊
was my feet up,
I was literally like feet in the air
我的右边屁股...
My right cheek was like...
呃 等下 是左半边屁股
Uh, no, wait, it's left cheek
都黑了
was just black
很多参赛选手抱怨说这不是危险
A lot these guy complain, it's not more dangerous
这简直就不能滑
it's just hard to skate
他们想越简单越好
and they want it to be as easy as possible
他们脑子中已经预先想好了动作
They know, like the trick they had on their mind
他们想要在比赛时做出这些杆子动作
they want to do on the rail in the contest
但是现在他们做不成了
They can't do now
因为场地太让人害怕了
'cause it's too scary
这个"大道具"对于冠军赛来说太好了
This big section is so good for the championship
因为你不知道谁会获胜 谁能冷静到最后
Because you have no idea who's gonna win it to the calms down at the end
这就是比赛场地吗
this is it?
是的
Yep
我们是在比赛前一个礼拜拿到场地的图纸
We got the course design one week prior to the event
所以比赛前的每一天
So every single day waiting up to it
你就只能等啊等啊等啊等啊
you are just waiting and waiting
and waiting and waiting for it
这些道具都太疯狂了
Things are crazy
这个台子看起来要人命的样子
This outledge right here is looking deadly
大家以及滑板圈里的人们
都难以相信他一次都还没拿下SL
It's unbelievable to every person and all of skateboarding that he hasn't won one
他基本上和NBA的Lebron James情况如出一辙
I would acquit it to almost like a Lebron type scenario
[现役NBA当家巨星Lebron James在全联盟技术数一数二 至今(指2012年)却无缘总冠军, 不过在2012-2013赛季如愿夺冠; 碰巧的是 Cole神也夺得2013年SL冠军]
大家都希望你成为冠军
You know, where every one
expects you to be a champion
你是现役最伟大的滑手之一
You're one of the greatest to ever do it
你仍然比其他人优秀
You're still better than everyone
仍然有招可以做
still have the trick to do it
为什么就拿不到冠军呢
Why are you not doing it?
哇 干得漂亮 Wyatt
Wow, good job! Wyatt!
不容易 真的很难做到
It's hard. It's really hard to say
全身心投入一个比赛并且
in a motor to fully get into a contest
以一种不能获胜的身体状态来赢得比赛
and win and be in a physical point you can't win
我早上6点起床
I got wake up on 6 am
喂好孩子 送他去上学
like get the kids fed, like ready to go school
把孩子送到学校 所有的行程都是固定的
Drop off my son to school, you have the whole routine
但是你很快就会被拉出来
It's really quick to just get pulled out
比如被生命的窃窃私语拉出来
by like, you know, the undertone of life
真的是太忙了 以至于1周都没滑板了
I've definitely been so busy
that I've not skated for a week
有时候我希望自己不用处理任何事情
At times, I wish that I could just not deal with anything
仅仅滑板而已
just do skateboarding
就像你感觉自己是个年轻小伙子
It's just like you would feel like a younger dude
没有妻儿 没有房子 没有公司 一无所有的状态
No kids, no wife, no house, no companies, none of it
每个动作之间都有细微的差别
There is so much nuance in each trick you know
它不像只是一个动作那么简单 而是如何接住板
it's not like just a kickflip, it's like how did he catch it
或者腿应该是怎么样的 手臂应该是什么姿势
or what were legs like, what were arms like
以及做的多高 多快
how high did he do it,
how fast he was going
就是这些细小的部分让滑板运动变得不断伟大
It's all these little things that make great skateboarding great skateboarding
对于我这个年龄的人来说这太不可思议了
That's pretty inconceivable for somebody of my age
我们小时候是在姑娘面前滑板
We grew up, God, feel if you could,
like skate in front of the girl
然后就能泡到妞
then you get a crush on highschool
这是你作为你自己争取得来的成就
That was like an accomplishment
that you got you as yourself
就好像这些人为了一两个人
It's like these guys are doing tricks that only
展示他们保留了十年的招
ten years ago reserved for one maybe two guys
而这个招可能需要一周才能搞定
and you know, it maybe took them a week to land it
但现在他们要在5到6次尝试中成功
but now they are doing it within five to six tries
为了达到职业水准 你可能会陷入困境 摔跤受伤
In order to get to professional level, you would have to be messed up, fallen and got hurt
很多次之后 你才能做成那些动作
more times then you'll land tricks
滑板真的能教会你什么是坚持和决心
It really teaches you persistance and determination
因为作为职业滑手这时学习Back tailslide
Because to learn the Back tailslide were at this point as a professional skater
就被认为是最基本的动作
is considered the basic trick
但当你还是个在学这招的孩子时
But when you're a little kid learning it
尝试这个动作可能会花费你好几周或数月
it took me weeks, months probably to finally get off trying it
一直一直一直一直一直尝试
over and over and over and over and over
最终你成了一个 你就会是世上最快乐的人
Finally you land one,
you're like the happiest person on the planet
因此滑板教会你不要太在意失败
So it teaches you the attitude of
not really understanding failure
在经历了滑板的顶峰 和之后的低潮
After being at the top of skateboarding, then falling off
直到现在又有机会闪耀
then getting this opportunity to shine again
如果他赢得比赛 许多公司就会为他抛出橄榄枝
if he wins, that's going to open all the doors from
来自板面和鞋子赞助商的代言协议
the endorsement deals to board
sponsors, to shoe sponsors
我年纪大了 和那些没有孩子的人相比
I got an age on, compares to ones that don't have kids
我觉得我有两颗心 一颗为了孩子着想
I feel like I have two hearts,
as to the one I have fall on them
第二颗代表我现在的年龄
then it's the two, it's the age that I have
当我觉得精疲力尽的时候 我不会再落后
When I feel tired, exhausted, I have no lags any more
我必须为孩子们着想
I just got think about my kids
我准备好了 就为了一个动作
And the battery is on charge, and it's for one trick
所以这很棒
So it's awesome, you know
个人而言 尤其是处在我现在这个人生阶段
For personally, and especially in the stage of my life today
两个孩子以及其他的一切
with my kids and everything
这将会是我生命中最有滋味的胜利
this would be the most tasteful victory in my life
因为我曾一直为了自己还有
自己的职业生涯和名誉参加比赛
Because I've been doing all those contest for myself, for my career, for my name
但是现在不仅仅是为了我自己
还有我的家庭和孩子
But now, it's not about me only,
like my family my son
应该会很棒的
It would be amazing
距离决赛还有5天
你好 伙计
What's up, buddy
Paul和世界上最好的滑手一起滑板 况且他们是朋友
Paul skates with the best in the world, those are friends
竞争性很强但是个友好的比赛
so it's a competitive thing
but it's a friendly competition
我不是那种刻意去练习
I don't look like as I got practicing
仅仅是一种冲动
It's just an urge
就像你想吃东西一样
No different than you got eat food
你有强烈的欲望 你必须做
you just have a creping and urge,
you have to do it
你得强迫自己去做
You've compelled to do it
这就是我在这练习的原因
that's what got me here
我就是强迫自己 我必须做 我喜欢这项运动
I'm just compelled, I have to do it, just I love it
我很幸运地成为一名著名的街式滑手
I'm blessing and fortunate to be one of the more recognized street skaters
我想仅仅是因为我能大胆去梦想
And I think it's only because
I had the element of dreaming big
我宁愿和SL中其他人一样
I would better be the same with
any other guy in Street League
能做成动作绝非偶然
it's no accident to be land it there
在这个比赛中 没人压力比他大
No one in this league has as much
pressure on them as Paul Roderiguez
他理应成为我们的Michael Jodan
He supposed to be our Michael Jodan
领着最高的薪水
hands down the highest pay
历史上的职业街头滑手
professional street skateboarder in history
他是Nike的信仰 Target的灵魂人物
he is the faith of Nike, Target!
Mtn Dew的当家滑手
This is Mountain Dew
他们不向Paul支付百万美元的薪水
They don't pay him millions of dollars
因为Paul一开始竟然处在第4的位置
because he should beginning fourth place
赢得SL会让你名声大噪
It's very prestigious to win a Street League event
但真的是太难了
It's nearly impossible
只有一部分人才敢说他们参加过
only a few guys can even say they've done it
并且只有少数才敢说他们是冠军
And even fewer can say they're champions
首届冠军
让我们为首届冠军Nyjah Huston欢呼吧
So give it up to Nyjah Huston
for being our first overall champion
SL成为了职业选手一年之中所必须的新赛事
It becomes the new element that is essential to a year of professional career
第二届冠军
你就是2011年SL的冠军
You, my friend, are the
2011 Street League champion
女士们先生们 让我们鼓掌喝彩
Give it up, ladies and gentlemen
这就像是NBA的头衔
it's like a NBA title, man
男音: 为什么SL是值得信赖的街式滑板比赛
Male voice: Why is Street League dependable street skateboarding contest?
因为没有什么更重要的了 其它的都弱爆了
Because there is nothing else matters,
everything else sucks
说真的呢
It's totally serious
很多其他的比赛
A lot the other contests
他们会有滑板 小轮车 摩托越野赛等等这些
they have skateboarding, BMX, motor cross, all that
我很尊重所有这些比赛
I got respect for all those other dissents
所以不要误解我
so don't get me wrong
但是大众总是把这些东西混为一谈
but like the general public combine all these together
就只是一项极限运动
it's just one action sports
而不是像那种看篮球赛 橄榄球赛
you don't go to a basketball
game and watch a football game
棒球赛等等都去同一个地方
你明白我的意思吧
and baseball game on the same place,
you know what I mean
所以SL是我们自己的场地
so it's like Street League is our own marina
我们自己的大舞台 属于我们的滑板
our own big stage, ours skateboarding
仅限于此
that's it
-你看来要去滑板吗   -You look to roll?
-是的   -Yeah, might you
呃 回见
Uh, see you when I get back
好的
OK
我有2年没和Nyjah一起生活
I had two years spent while
I didn't have Nyjah with my presence
我不断挣扎就是为了让孩子回到我身边
And I struggle to the courses to get my children back
当我重新取得他们的抚养权时
And when I got them back
他们身上的负能量真的真的很严重
that's when a lot negative energy
was really really present
在没有我的情况下 他们刚和他们的父亲度过两年
They have just been two years with their dad without me
他们的父亲给他们一直说是我毁了这个家
And he had basically brainwashed
them that I had ruined the family
说我抛弃了他们 嗯...
and I abandoned them, and um...
所以当我第一次从法庭上夺回孩子们的时候
so when I first got them back from the courts
我居然成坏人了
I mean, I was like the bad guy
Nyjah当时也在审判室
Nyjah was actually in the courtroom
他的父亲认为把他带入法庭比较好
His dad thought it was a good idea to unwind to bring Nyjah into the courtroom
然后法官看着Nyjah 说到
And the judge looked at Nyjah, and said
你说你两年没见你的母亲了
you're telling me you haven't
seen our mother in two years
Nyjah说他在比赛现场见过我一次
and he said, when I saw her one time, she was in the stands at the contest
然后法官说 今天你就要和母亲在一起了
And the judge was like, well,
you were going with your mom today
然后就这样
and that was it
我必须得生拉硬拽才把他带上车
then I had to physically get him into the car
就是这样
Yeah
我把Nyjah带回来的时候 他才15
When I got Nyjah back, he was 15
当我第一次带他回家
And when I first got him back
他完全不能和他的同龄人处得来
he was completely unsocialized with the peer
他将永远不会有朋友
he would never have friends
永远不会和女孩子交往
he'd never have relationship with the girl
他自己都不知道怎么做
He didn't know what to do with himself
因为他从未有过自由
because he'd never had freedom
他从没有选择穿衣的自由
He'd never have freedom to choose
what kind of clothes to wear
或是选择听音乐的自由
or to choose what kind
of music he's like listen to
和选择吃东西的自由
or to choose what kind
of food he likes to eat
我人生的前15年是很空虚的
I was raised vacant for
the first 15 years in my life
我老爸超级无聊
My dad was really strictly vacant
我觉得他现在完全正常了 完全地
I think he's completely normal now, completely
我确定的是他现在周围总有朋友陪着
One thing that I do know is that he feels that he always has friends around him
弥补了过去失去的那些日子
making up for the lost time
在比赛的前几个晚上我要避免聚会
Yeah, I just got try to keep myself from party a couple nights before the contest
这样我可以集中注意力 保证足够的休息
so stay focused and make sure I get good rest
对 有时在决赛那夜之前就太疯狂了
Yeah, sometimes it's crazy before the night of finals
上个我赢的地形赛前一晚 最后都累的不行了
The last on terrain contest I won, too straight lazy to go
在比赛前我才睡了3个小时
I got like three hours to sleep before the contest
太疯了
that was crazy
是啊 不知为什么我仍能打起精神
Yeah, somehow I still have to pull together
但是这个绝对是足够重要的
but this one is definetly important enough
我不会再那么做了
I'm not gonna let that happen
现在Nyjah有自己的房子了
Nyjah now has his own house
男音: 那只兔子在哪
嗯 现在我也不知道
Uh, I'm afraid I don't know right now
男音: 还是不和你玩?
Male voice: still split?
Nyjah Huston: 是啊 我没时间管那个小家伙
Nyjah Huston:  Yeah, I just don't have time to take care of that little shit
我觉得让他们躁起来很酷
I mean, it's cool to annoy them
Nyjah母亲: 对我来说 看他经历这些过程是一种乐趣
Nyjah's mom: For me, it's fun to watch him go through the process
因为刚开始的时候
你过去的时候会发现孩子们
because at first, you know you
go over and there're just kids
睡在角落里 桌子下面 他们总是在睡觉
sleeping at every corner, kid sleeping under the table, kids sleep always
现在Nyjah会和这些朋友找些事做
and now, he's waiting out the permanent visitors
男音: 别再说昨晚的怪物鸡鸡了
Male voice: Please don't talk about the
chicken monster last night
天啊
Dude
帅哈
it's insane
我有次一晚上泡了六个妞
I've got over six girls coming over a night
哈哈哈
hahaha
我欣慰的是看着他自己做出选择 犯些错误
For me it's beautiful to watch him
have choices and make mistakes
对于一个孩子来说 亲历成长的过程很重要
It's important for a kid to go through that
他以前从没自己体验过 他过去别无选择
it was he not having that before, he had no choice
这是第一笔电费账单 我看过了
It's the first Edison electricity bill, I'm pretty sure
你要处理这个了
You're beginning to handle this
怎么在线支付  咋整
How to online pay a bill? How to?
收电费的肯定不收现金啦
He'll not got for the cash, obviously
能用信用卡支付吗
Can I pay by a card?
可以 可以打电话搞定
Yeah, I can call and do it
你可以打电话或是网上操作 都行
hey, you can call it or do it online, it's crazy
男音: 那他的父亲现在在哪
Male voice: So where is his dad now?
他不向我们透露
Well, he doesn't reveal that to us
当孩子们收到他寄来的生日礼物包裹时
When the children have gotten a
package on their birthday from him
他用了他母亲的地址作为回信地址
he used his mother's address
as we returned address
然而最后信却最终出现在了洛杉矶的邮局
But it's stamped in Los Angeles zip coff, at the Los Angeles post office
所以我也只能猜测他现在住在洛杉矶附近
So that I can only assume that he's in the Los Angeles area
对 我很久没和他联系了 嗯...
Yeah, I haven't talked him for a while, I mean, like
我愿意和他说话 但是
I would love to talk to him, but I mean
自从过去分开之后他从未联系过我
he's never contacted me through out the past time
所以我不会违背自己的意愿去联系他
So, I mean, I'm not gonna go out my way to contact him
因为他作为一个父亲应该明白
Because he's like the father figuring it out
我觉得这更像是他对我的责任
I just feel like that's more of his responsibility to mine
不管发生什么 我还是他的儿子
No matter what happens, I'm still his son
对于我的兄弟姐妹们也是一样的
And it goes out with my brothers and little sisters too
他们也很久没和他说话了
they haven't talked to him for a while
我希望他能回来
hopefully he comes around soon
我仍然愿意和他有个良好的关系
I'd love to still have a good relationship with him
我认为那样就挺好
I think it would be awesome
距离决赛还有3天
对我而言 Ryan Sheckler生来永不满足 充满欲望
Ryan Sheckler to me is born of hunger and desire
而且他获得过无数的荣誉
And he's been right on the
door of steps so many times
在所有比赛中他都滑的很努力
He skates so hard in every event
你可以看到他对于能够得到东西的渴望
you see the hunger of what he's capable of
但是他还没赢过SL
but he has yet to win one
他滑遍每个仓库 滑板场以及每一个能滑的场地
He's skating every warehouse, every park and every place he possibly can right now
这是对他进入今年比赛坚韧意志的一次测试
That is a testment of his fortitude
to try to come in here this year
而这又能为冠军做好预热
And free gate put a nail
on the comfy of championship
我要统统赢回来 我想要夺冠
I want to win them all,
I want to win all of them
必须想办法做到这一点
And it just has to work it out
继去年冠军赛的表现之后
After last year's performance in the championship
我就知道Sheckler肯定要证明一些东西了
I know Sheckler defintely has something to prove
他不是那种首轮就被淘汰靠第2次机会翻身的角色
he wasn't the first guy get eliminated then they give him a chance at the title
听别人说Ryan江郎才尽 听得都听烦了
It's tiring to see people say- Ryan's done, Ryan's done
他才23岁啊
He's 23 years old
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
我们现在是在做品牌的阶段
We're promoting brands
只有我们自己说完的时候才是真的完
we're done when we say we're done
千万别提早下结论
We're not done
但赢得SL对于Ryan来说是遥手可及了
but winning the Street League
woule be kinda close for Ryan
TranSkate译制
(Sheckler是)我最强劲的对手
Toughest competitor of me
无论何时都全力以赴
Puts 100% on the line no matter what
他从来都没有所谓保守的战略
He never goes a safe hour
我这次肯定会用一些新招
I'm gonna pull off some new
tricks for this one for sure
一些Nollie动作
A couple of Nollie tricks
一些反脚动作
a couple of switch tricks
我最近一直在练习Fullcab flip
And I've been working on the Fullcab flip a lot
因为我喜欢这个动作 做的也不错
Because I like that trick and it does well for me
狠狠的摔一跤要么会让你很疼
Taking a solid slam can either really hurt you
要么会让你很生气
Or just piss you off
对我来说 一般会让我很生气
And for me, it normally just pisses me off
很疼 但是会让你想要欺骗自己的大脑
It hurts but it's more like a energy meant to trick your brain
对自己说 "不疼 再试一次"
Be like "that didn't hurt. We are doing this again"
一旦连续摔个四五次以后
Once it gets like the fourth or the fifth hard slam in a row
你就会重新考虑自己在做什么
then you kinda reevaluate what you are trying
第一步 别做胆小鬼
Step one, don't be a pussy
第二步 坚持
Step two, commit
啊 我操
Aw you mother(fucker)
再来一次 再来一次
Man let's do it, let's do it
SL里没有比他更有名的职业滑手了
There is no more famous professional skateboarder in Street League than him
由此他得到了大量的认可和百万计的财富
And with that comes this massive endorsement deals and millions of dollars
人们认为你会赢
You are expected to win
你是Ryan Sheckler 你只能赢
You are Ryan Sheckler, all you do is win
这样的压力在前几年就对他影响很大
That pressure in the first years was mind-blowing for him
不玩了
I give up
纽约: 明日开战
这些人来到一个新的城市 适应时间只有1天
These guys show up in a new city and they have one day to feel it out
稍微整顿一下 第二天就要比赛
get comfortable with it,
and then the next day, the contest is on
男音: Chris 你感觉怎么样
Male voice: How are you feeling Chris?
Chris Cole: 酸疼 非常非常酸疼
Chris Cole: Sore, really really sore
我来这里希望得到一个Chris Cole式的胜利
I'm here trying to get a Chris Cole victory man
嘿 我也正有此意
Hey you know what, that makes two of us
第11次比赛了啊
Eleven contests in
已经有这么多次了吗
Is that how many it's been?
我哭了11次了
I've cried eleven tears
你再打蜡的话我就要开罚单了
You keep waxing that you gonna catch a fine
我们有针对你们这些家伙打蜡的罚款
We have wax fines for you comes from valley
如果有人卡住了 然后摔花脸怎么办
你们会向他们付钱吗
会的 会的啦
Yes, we'll do it, pay it back
这玩意儿糟透了 伙计
噢 天啊
Oh my God
道具真大
The thing's big
真的非常大
This is really big actually
"大道具"真的很大 很恐怖
The big section is big. They are scary
在大绝招比赛我做的那些动作
Like normally trying those tricks
that I would try in the big section
在街道上的话 我尝试一次之前要试滑10-20次
If I was in the street, I'll be rolling up ten fifteen twenty times before I even try it once
但是你必须在这里做 马上就做
But you have to try it right there,
you have to try it right now
男音: 你在做大招之前 会对着帽子说话
Male voice: So before you attempt
a big trick, you talk into your hat
你说了些什么
What do you say?
Paul Rodriguez: 我只是在祈祷
Paul Rodriguez: I'm just saying a prayer
寻求庇护
ask for the protection
我认为我是一个有信仰的人
I consider myself a man of faith
相信有更高的能量
Believing in a higher power
我觉得一句祷告就够了
I feel like one prayer is good enough
所以我的祈祷几乎变成了强迫症
So my prayers have developed almost into like OCD
越紧张越要这么做
Like the more nervous I get,
the more I feel compelled to do that
Nyjah 相比于其他比赛你有多想获得这个比赛的胜利
Nyjah, how do bad do you want the trophy of this contest versus other contest that you've chased?
非常想 真的
So bad, yeah
这是我最重要的一次比赛
By far the most important one
而且 上一站比赛结果不佳
And also, I won't say that was good that a loss last stop
这也是我为什么这么想赢的原因之一...
and I think that's another reason I have a lot of motivation to...
你们好啊啊啊
What uuuuup
我要去找Sheckler了
I gotta go find Sheckler
场地很大
Course is big
摔跤很疼
And it hurts
我喜欢比赛 所以我们来这里
I love competing, that's why we do it
我们有一个笑话- 亚军就是最大的输家
We have a running joke- second place is a first loser
我这么说的时候别人就会生气
Everybody gets mad at me when I say that
但是我和我的儿子们会找到其中的笑点
but my sons and I, we take the comedy out of that
第2名 你就是最大的失败者
second place, you are the first loser
当然不是失败者 但是我们想赢
of course it's not a loser, but we wanna win
自Ryan出生以来
From the moment Ryan was born
我们做的一切
whatever we did
Ryan看我们作为整个家庭所做的一切
and whatever Ryan witnessed us doing as a family
都是想要赢
we did it to win it
就连公司野餐时做的游戏我们都要赢
Anything from a company picnic where Grinch and I were doing a sack potato race
and a wheel barrel race, Grinch and I had to win
对Ryan来说也是这样
And Ryan got all that
明天走起!
Let's swing tomorrow!
走起!!
Swinging head off!!
晚安
Good night
明天见
See you tomorrow
小男孩声音: 嘿 Sheckler...
Boy voice: Yo Sheckler...
在SL的任何人都是这个星球上最好的滑手
Every guy, who was there at Street League
is as good as it gets on this planet earth
这么说来 之所以有人获胜有人失败
So, the difference between one guy winning another
不是天赋的原因
is not talent
都是精神上的原因 是你如何处理这样的压力
It's all mental, it's all how you handle that pressure
或者你是否把它当成压力
or do you even perceive it as pressure
如果你一到那里精神上就被击败了的话
It you go there already mentally defeated then
那和不去比赛的效果是一样的
you might as well just not even
get on the plane to go there
所有人的水平都是相近的
Everyone is on a similar talent level
真正改变处境的并不是水准上的差异
It's not the talent that really changes the situation
而是你的出发点
it's where you head out
男音: 你觉得今晚谁会赢
Male voice: Who do you think is gonna win tonight?
Nyjah或者P-Rod
Nyjah or P-Rod
或者Char Ortiz 谁都有可能
Or Chaz Ortiz, anybody
Rob Dyrde你能一手策划这个场地和赛事实在是太伟大了
Rob Dyrdek, you really outdid yourself
With this course with this championship man
生命中有那么一天 你倾尽全力来争夺冠军
You have one day to skate your life on the line to become the champion
这里每一个人都想获胜
I mean everyone of this guys is so hungry
我-我自己都感到紧张了 我知道他们的感受
and I-I'm already feeling the nerves in my gut, I know how they are feeling
在解说介绍完所有人 灯都打开以后
So after everyone gets introduced
and most lights turned on
就是比赛的时间了
that's when it's go time
第一轮 线
男解说员: Back tailslide 然后滑向quarter pipe
Male Narrator: Back tailslide, coming in hot to the quarter pipe gap
Frontside ollie 非常轻松
Frontside ollie, so effortlessly
毫不费力的Nosegrind 风格很好
Lazing through that Nosegrind, it's a great style
喔...
Wo...
超大的kickflip结束了这一轮
Huge kickflip! He cleaned up that run
Colin Kennedy: 当年Bastien参加比赛的时候
Colin Kennedy: Contests when Bastien was entering them
和现在的比赛已经完全不同了
to contests are now,
have changed so dramatically
现在他回来了 但如今是新生代的天下
Now he has come back
but it's like its whole new generation
现在的时代属于Chaz 属于Nyjah 属于P-Rod
It's the Chaz's, the Nyjah's, the P-Rod's
这些人对于动作和战术的要求如手术刀般精准
These guys are like, surgical with their tricks and there approach
Bastien则是比较野性的那种风格
and it's like Bastien is a little bit more of a wild kind
男解说员: Bastien Salabanzi是个老手
Male Narrator: Bastien Salabanzi is not a rookie
你听到Rob整个赛季都说这家伙很可能能得到冠军
and you heard Rob all season saying this guy could easily be a champion this year
Chase Gabor: 肯定是SL让他复出的
Chase Gabor: 100% Street League kinda brought him back
回到了他一直应得的聚光灯下
into the spot light that he deserved the whole time
男解说员: 看来他在按摩痉挛的部位
Male Narrator: Looks like he's nursing a cramp there
使劲 使劲, 使劲 使劲 使劲 使劲 使劲 使劲 使劲
Push push, push push push push push push push
收缩 收缩 收缩
contract contract contract
记住 那边疼这边就收缩
remember, if you crap here, contract here
好的
OK
疼痛声: 啊...
Pain voice: ah...
我理解你的感受 别紧张 放轻松
I know, I understand, make it easy, there it is
感觉怎么样
Is it OK?
Bastien Salabanzi: 当时非常疼 但也非常激动
Bastien Salabanzi: It was super painful, but also with aldreline
8小时的飞机 将近12小时的旅行
I mean 8 hour flight, almost 12 hour trip to be there
我不会因为这样的事情退出的
I was not gonna let such things to get in my way
所以我试着不顾疼痛继续比赛
So I try to skate pass that
Colin Kennedy: 现在对于Nyjah来说
Colin Kennedy: It must be pretty bizarre now for Nyjah
他的父亲不在看台上肯定很奇怪
to not even see his dad in the stands
Njyah Huston和你说过他认为这是他这辈子最重要的比赛
Male Narrator: Nyjah Huston told you he feels this is the most important contest of his life
Nyjah夺冠的话可能对他自己和他妈妈意义都很大
Colin Kennedy: Nyjah taking the championship this year probably would mean a lot to both himself and his mom
男解说员: 非常进攻性的风格
Male Narrator: That was offensive
Colin Kennedy: 这意味着Nyjah自己成长了起来
Colin Kennedy: It kinda shows Nyjah is blossoming into his own
而不是靠着父亲的教导成为冠军
and is not really relying on his father's
tutor to be a champion
男解说员: Nyjah Huston在过去几年
Nyjah Huston has been the most dominant man
一直是滑板比赛中最具霸主地位的人物
in competitive skateboarding to the last few years
男解说员2: 我觉得他可能超过Sheckler
这是一个很厉害的结束动作
Male Narrator 2: Oh I think he might catch Sheckler that was a strong finishing
男解说员: 果不其然 被你说中了
Male Narrator: There it is, you called it
你说过他不喜欢落后 即使是落后0.1分
you said he does not like to be at the bottom even it's by a tenth of a point
Luan Oliveira: 我可从没参加过这种比赛 我现在很紧张
Luan Oliveira: I've never been to this contest, really nervous
我不知道该怎么搞定那个必玩的扶手
I don't know how I'm gonna
skate that rail I have to
男音: 扶手怎么了
What's wrong with the rail?
太大了 简直巨大
So big, it's huge
男音: 太难了吗
Male voice: Just gnarly?
是啊 我得闭上眼睛 完全做不到
Yeah, I just gotta close my eyes and, no
不管了
Fuck it
[呼了?]
男解说员: 来自巴西的年轻人Luan Oliveira
Male Narrator: The young man from Brazil
这是他在SL的第一个决赛
Luan Oliveira his first final in Street League
马上在街道环节出场
Here he is in the run section
Rob 你那边怎么样 我们在评论Luan
Rob how are you,
so we were just commenting on Luan
还有他在淘汰赛感受到的压力
and the pressure that he knows
with this elimination run
Rob Dyrdek: 外面很冷 当你参加这种级别的赛事
Rob Dyrdek: Yeah it cold out here. When you are at this level of competition
还有这样的压力 你必须要全力以赴
with this much pressure,
you gotta put it down what it matters man
这样的话 他出局了
with that he is eliminated
Luan|出局|
Luan Oliveira: 我知道我不可能夺冠 但...
我能来这里就很幸运了
能和P-Rod那些人一起比赛就很高兴了 很棒
接下来
大绝招环节
第二轮 大绝招
男解说员: 5次机会确定最后分数
Male Narrator: Five attempts, one score
Chaz, krooked grind nollie flip out
非常轻松
So effortless
哦 哇哦 天啊
oh whoa, man
Bastien Salabanzi现在必须要全力以赴了
Bastien Salabanzi, now he needs to really assert himself
完美!
Perfect!
耶 这才是他的节奏 真不愧是激动哥啊!
Yeah, he's right here, Captain excitement!
他能把热情传递给人群
He relishes the crowd the excitement
我希望他能完成动作
and I wanted him to come in
and put that trick down
然后用力捶自己的胸口 脱掉外套 来个月球漫步
and pound his chest double pissant and moonwalk
他真的是一个特殊的人
Really he's just the most unique individual
奇怪的 有特点的人
eccentric, a classic individual
我觉得他是滑板界的莫罕默德
and I think he is the Mohammed in skateboarding
男解说员: 看看他的笑容
Male Narrator: Look at the smile on his face!
我实际上会祈祷他表现的好
I actually like pray for him to do well
因为我真的希望看见他激动的样子
Cause I really want to see how hyped he is
嗯 他让我很开心
and like, he makes me happy
Chris Cole现在面临着出局的危险
Male Narrator: Chris Cole now sitting in that elimination spot, he is at risk
9分以上!
9 Club!
下一个是Paul Rodriguez
Next up, Paul Rodriguez
Nollie krooked grind nollie front foot flip out!
9.8!
有了这个分数 Paul暂列第一名
With that Paul, in first
Sean和Ryan面临被淘汰的危险
下一个是2012的卫冕冠军Sean Malto
Up next 2012 defending champion, Sean Malto
很高的cabflip
Huge cabflip
落地的时候没有稳住
Loses up a little bit at the landing
Sean Malto应该做些保守的动作
Sean Malto could use some insurance here
因为Sheckler很容易追上他
'cause Sheckler could touch him fairly simply
还有一次机会 如果Sheckler成了的话
With just one run to go if Sheckler has a make
可能就是Malto出局了
Malto could be that guy in the bubble
Sheckler要出一个高分的动作
Sheckler's gotta go big here
一定要超过Sean Malto
Definitely wanna switch seat with Sean Malto
Sheckler父亲: 我当时非常紧张
Sheckler's dad: I was very nervous
能听见在看台上的人在加油
You hear the people in the stands rooting against
我装作没听见 认真看比赛
I try to block it out and go
into that championship
我一直想保持正能量
I was just really trying to
channel a positive energy
男解说员: 这是Sheckler 要离开被淘汰的位置
Male Narrator: Here is Sheckler, needs to get out of the spot
这个比上个还差一些
Oh man, that was a little bit worse
than the other one that he did
所以这个应该也没有得分
So I don't think that one's
getting scored, yeah he laid it out
Sean Malto要为自己得点分
Sean Malto needs to put
some pad on his score
Sheckler就在他身后被淘汰的位置
as Sheckler is right behind him on that bubble spot
Nosegrind 最后卡了一下
Nosegrind, sticks at the end
他的命运现在掌握在Ryan Sheckler的手中
He is now in the seat and watch his
destiny in Ryan Sheckler's hands
男解说员2: 真是疯狂
Male Narrator 2: That's crazy
男解说员: Malto的未来在他手中
Male Narrator: Malto's future in his hands
他自己的未来也在他手中 在此一举
Sheckler's future in his hands, here it is
卫冕冠军出局
We've lost our champion
Sean|出局|
我们的卫冕冠军Sean Malto现在退场了
Our defending champion Sean Malto
is on the sidelines right now
最后一轮 大道具
现在领先的是P-Rod
And P-Rod's in the lead
Rob 你认为大道具环节会发生什么？
Rob, how do you think it's gonna go
down here in the big section?
肯定会是一场血战
It's gonna be a full flesh battle
这里每一个人都想要获胜
I mean every one of these
guys wants to win it
他们的分数也非常接近
They are all so close in points
最终要看谁能做出4个最难的动作
and it's gonna come down to who can do the four absolute hardest tircks
在这些危险的大道具上
on this very dangerous big section
Ryan Sheckler刚才和我说他每次失误
Ryan Sheckler just told me every time that he fails
都很讨厌这些东西 因为会伤到他的脚
he hates this thing because it's killing his feet
但是我对他说20分钟以后
可能就是你捧着冠军的奖杯了
but I told him twenty more minutes you could be hoisting up the championship trophy
男解说员: 在6轮比赛之后
At the end of these six attempts
我们就能决出冠军了
we are going to have a champion
Bastien第一个上
Bastien will be first
Bastien在这个赛季的大道具环节中
The best score that Salabanzi has this season
获得的最高分是9.2
in the big section a 9.2
他现在就需要这样的分数
that's what he needs right now
我右腿抽筋了 如果我 如果我...
I've a cramp in my right leg, if I, if I...
你只有五分钟 我只能做这么多了
Bastien Salabanzi: 嘿 我们有5分钟的时间...
Bastien Salabanzi: Hey we got 5 minutes...
Bastien Salabanzi: 非常疼
Bastien Salabanzi: It was super painful
医生声音: 如果你非常紧张的话 就做深呼吸
Doctor voice: If you're not nervous, not breathing
控制住
Stop that shit
调整呼吸 集中注意力
Breathe and focus
动一动 动一动
Move around, Move around
动起来 动起来 动起来 动起来
move move move move move
运动 本能地运动起来
motion, origin motion
Bastien Salabanzi: 拼了!!
Bastien Salabanzi: Let's do it!!
男解说员: 激动哥 我们来看看他有什么招
Male Narrator: Captain excitement, anything goes here, let's see what he's got
这是Salabanzi第2次失误
That's the second fail for Salabanzi
这样他就无缘冠军了
That is going to take him out
of the championship conversation
Bastien|出局|
轮到Chaz Ortiz
Here is Chaz Ortiz
他下面两个动作的得分很重要
His next two scores are critically
他必须要完成一个动作 至少4.7分
he has to make it, he needs a 4.7
Chaz Ortiz必须要得到6.2分以上的分数
Chaz Ortiz needs to drop that low score of a 6.2
他需要9.1分
He needs a 9.1
得了7.8分
A 7.8 for Chaz
Chaz|出局|
她还好
She's alright
她只是太激动了
Chris, Ryan, Nyjah和Paul
还有争夺冠军的机会
记得Rob之前和我说过
Remember when Rob told me earlier
没有人用最后一招赢过SL
no one has ever won Street League
by making their last trick
Chris Cole需要9.1分 他有能力得到这个分数
Chris Cole needs a 9.1 and he's capable of it
他又向外围的台子滑去
He's heading for the outer ledge again
非常稳健的战术
Solid! Strategist!
这个排名在整个大绝招比赛中
This leader board is gonna slide up and down
肯定会有很大的变动
through this whole big section
厉害！
Incredible!
需要6.0分 得到8.9分
Needed a 6.0, gets a 8.9
Kickflip backside lipslide
Switch backside 50
Paul Rodriguez凭借7.5分重新领先
7.5 Paul Rodriguez back to the lead
唇语: 开玩笑吧
Lip read: Come on
比赛即将结束的时候 每一次机会都很重要
Every try counts towards the end
Ryan Sheckler 需要8.1分
Ryan Sheckler needs an 8.1
哦 他没有接到这个Hardflip
oh that Hardflip gets away from him
为Ryan Sheckler鼓掌
Make some noise for Ryan Sheckler
Ryan|出局|
压抑的情绪像龙卷风一样
It was just an emotional depression hurricane
席卷我们每一个人 也包括他
came over everybody and him included
现在想想都觉得难受
It chokes up me right now
even thinking about it
真的很不好受
but yeah it was a bad deal
Ryan不喜欢失败 我们都不喜欢
You know, Ryan hates to lose, we all do
Nyjah Huston暂时领先
Nyjah Huston is currently in the lead
得有人站出来给他一点压力
Someone gonna give him a challenge
Chris Cole 需要9.1分
Chris Cole needs his 9.1
哦 他往后摔了
Oh, he just falls back
Chirs|出局|
观众呐喊声: Cole Cole Cole...
看来那天发挥良好的人并不是我
It was so happened that there is the other dude
that just ripped that day
失误1-2个动作就出局了
One or two misses you are
suddenly out of the conversation
早先我们就知道比赛肯定不会这么简单
Early on, we did not look like it was gonna be easier
最后捧起这个奖杯的人肯定是实至名归的
Whoever hoists this trophy at end of the day deserves it
Kickflip frontside nose slide
肯定是目前为止在这个杆子上完成的最难动作之一
Definitely one of the most difficult tricks down on this rail so far
他回到了他想到的地方 领先的位置
His is back where he likes to be, in the lead!
注意 Nyjah到现在还没一次失误
For note, Nyjah has not missed a trick
来自Street League简报
the Street League shoot out
Paul! Switch crooked gind
P-Rod这招得了7.3分
That will be 7.3 for P-Rod
又回到了第1名
back now into first place
Nyjah可没怎么碰到过这种情况
This is not common in Nyjah territory
Nyjah Huston 270 Backside lipslide
排名又往前迈进了
Taking a couple of steps to leader board
他需要3.5分 却得了8.3分
All he needed was a 3.5 and a 8.3
一跃成为第1名
Right to the top
3招以来第1次失误
First fail after three in a row
可以看到他很失望
You can see the frustration
他应该是有机会大幅度拉开比分的
He had the opportunity to really open up the gap
就是现在了!
Here we are!
最后一次尝试
Final attempt
最关键的时刻!
This is it!
仅剩的两名选手Nyjah和Paul Rodriguez
It's coming down to Nyjah and Paul Rodriguez
Nyjah的Cab back lip to fakie 没成功
Oh Nyjah Cab back lip to fakie washes out
Paul Rodriguez只要得到7.3分
Paul Rodriguez needs a 7.3
就能成为2012年SL的冠军
to be the 2012 Street League champion
从来没人用最后一招赢得过冠军
No one has ever won the
championship before on the last trick
Paul能不能成为第一个呢
Can Paul be the first?
真是吓人
That was so scary
告诉大家成为冠军是什么感觉
Tell the people what it feels like to be the champion
感觉很棒 到位了
It feels awesome and it feels right
去年的比赛感觉太糟糕了 简单来说赢了前三场
What happened last year was so wrong to put it simply now to win the first three
但很不走运 没拿下总冠军
and unfortunately, not be able to
take down the championship
所以这也是我今年夺冠的动力
so that was all my motivation
to make it happen this year
简直不能更高兴了
I just couldn't be happier
那可能是他一生中最美的一天
That's probably one of the best days of his life
他是那么的激动
I mean he was so so so excited
为这个孩子喝彩吧
Give it up to this kid
男音: 对你来说也是一样的吧
Male voice: and you were too?
是的
Yes
Cole神在自家前院为自己和儿子Wyatt建了个板场
未来"街头联赛"的冠军[最终在2013年如愿夺冠]
Chaz Ortiz参与了由Colin Kennedy执导
为Gatorade功能饮料拍摄的广告片
他仍然在奋力争取"街头联赛"冠军
Luan Olivera被大赞助商Nike签下
2013年3月 他用Tampa Pro冠军震惊了世界
Ryan Sheckler飞往中国拍摄他的新片段
那将作为整个全球片段的一部分
都是些从来没人玩过的地形
Sean Malto返回堪萨斯城
现正在训练以求赢回冠军头衔
Paul Rodriguez为他和小女
Heaven买下一所房子
那儿离他成长的地方只有5分钟路程
Bastien回到法国继续滑板 拍片 养育孩子
Lil Wayne虔诚地参加每一届的"街头联赛"
他很兴奋地告诉我们
他最近做成了Pop shoveit下3阶
2013年 Rob Dyrdek把"街头联赛"扩展到了3大洲总共8站
他的下一个大梦想就是见证滑板运动进入奥运会
TranSkate译制